export const ARTISTS = [
    {
        id: 1,
        name: 'Dimitar Dimov',
        title: 'Tenor Saxophone',
        age: 22,
        town: 'Veliko Tarnovo, Bulgaria',
        description: [
            {
                question: 'What initially inspired you to choose your music instrument and study it?',
                answer: 'The thing that inspired me the most was the natural sound of the instrument and how versatile it can be.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Who is your favourite artist/composer? ',
                answer: 'I have more than one favorite artist, but let’s say in the last two years I have listened mostly to: Sonny Stitt, Cannonball Adderley, Charlie Parker, Dizzy Gillespie, The Jazz Messengers and Joshua Redman.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What is your favourite music genre?',
                answer: 'Jazz and more specifically the subgenre: Hard-Bop.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Could you share a memorable moment from your musical journey so far? ',
                answer: 'Last year’s tour around Bulgaria with a couple of friends from the conservatory: Simeon Simeonov, Nedelcho Ninov, Dimitris Bakopoulos, SongYi Lee.                    ',
            },
            {
                question: 'How do you think music has evolved so far?',
                answer: 'So far so good, but I am a bit skeptical about the future.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What advice would you give to young musicians who want to pursue music as a career?',
                answer: 'Listen more music, be familiar with the history of music and how things happened and why, do what you like not what is needed!                     ',
            },
            {
                question: 'Can you share any upcoming projects you’re excited about? ',
                answer: 'Spring Gala in Groningen, Summer tour in Bulgaria, Bansko Jazz Festival (Bulgaria).',
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        id: 2,
        name: 'Ivo Stoyanov',
        title: 'Percussion',
        age: 20,
        town: 'Ruse, Bulgaria',
        description: [
            {
                question: 'What initially inspired you to choose your music instrument and study it?',
                answer: 'Actually, I cannot remember how it inspired me to choose percussion but I could say since I was a child, I started to play with different things such as tables, woods, plates and therefore I started to study percussion and piano.                    ',
            },
            {
                question: 'Who is your favourite artist/composer? ',
                answer: 'I have a lot of artists and composers who are inspiring me every day but for now, the composers and artists who developed me as a musician are Emil Tabakov, Martin Grubinger, Keiko Abe and Steve Reich.                    ',
            },
            {
                question: 'What is your favourite music genre?',
                answer: 'Contemporary music and jazz music and the combination of them.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Could you share a memorable moment from your musical journey so far? ',
                answer: 'To be accepted in the school which I wanted to be and also two years ago when I performed the Prism Rhapsody by Keiko Abe in my hometown city which was the third performance ever in Bulgaria.',
            },
            {
                question: 'How do you think music has evolved so far?',
                answer: 'In general, music has changed a lot through the time and it’s continuing to do so, but the most important thing is how the music is connecting everyone around us.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What advice would you give to young musicians who want to pursue music as a career?',
                answer: 'To believe in themselves and to know that everything is possible instead of the consequences which they have!',
            },
            {
                question: 'Can you share any upcoming projects you’re excited about? ',
                answer: 'In June there is going to be a world premiere of a piece which I have written for violin and percussion. Also, now I am doing my first concerto for chamber orchestra and percussion which I really hope it’s going to be performed during the Chamber music week in December. Then, during the summer I will have several concerts with the Rousse Philharmonic orchestra and in October I will perform with them as a soloist.                    ',
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        id: 3,
        name: 'Nedelcho Ninov',
        title: 'Trombone',
        age: 25,
        town: 'Panagyirishte, Bulgaria',
        description: [
            {
                question: 'What initially inspired you to choose your music instrument and study it?',
                answer: 'Long story short, all my friends started playing trombone, I tried playing it and took a liking to it.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Who is your favourite artist/composer? ',
                answer: 'I don’t play favourites, but the most inspiring to me were Red Hot Chilli Peppers, J.J. Johnson and Gustav Mahler.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What is your favourite music genre?',
                answer: 'Whatever I currently play the most, which is jazz.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Could you share a memorable moment from your musical journey so far? ',
                answer: 'Too many good moments to think of one, when other people are involved it’s always memorable.',
            },
            {
                question: 'How do you think music has evolved so far?',
                answer: 'For the better, for the most part.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What advice would you give to young musicians who want to pursue music as a career?',
                answer: 'Work,work,work.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Can you share any upcoming projects you’re excited about? ',
                answer: 'The Spring Gala, of course!',
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        id: 4,
        name: 'Simeon Simeonov',
        title: 'Drums & Percussion',
        age: 24,
        town: 'Plovdiv, Bulgaria',
        description: [
            {
                question: 'What initially inspired you to choose your music instrument and study it?',
                answer: 'My parents just dropped me off in the music school’s percussion department.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Who is your favourite artist/composer? ',
                answer: 'Roy Hargrove at the moment.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What is your favourite music genre?',
                answer: 'Jazz between the 40s and 60s',
            },
            {
                question: 'Could you share a memorable moment from your musical journey so far? ',
                answer: 'A certain concert I had in high school with my chamber music ensemble at a festival in Croatia.',
            },
            {
                question: 'How do you think music has evolved so far?',
                answer: 'Pretty well.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What advice would you give to young musicians who want to pursue music as a career?',
                answer: 'Start early and don’t forget about the basics.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Can you share any upcoming projects you’re excited about? ',
                answer: 'The Spring Gala and my upcoming summer gigs.',
            },
            {
                question: 'We used a recording of yours on one of our posts, what inspired you to record this tune?',
                answer: 'I was in a Horace Silver mood.',
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        id: 5,
        name: 'Tsveta Boneva',
        title: 'Violin',
        age: 23,
        town: 'Ruse, Bulgaria',
        description: [
            {
                question: 'What initially inspired you to choose your music instrument and study it?',
                answer: 'My sister was a very big part of this decision. I was only 5 when I started and listening to her play every day inspired me and I wanted to be like my big sister. ',
            },
            {
                question: 'Who is your favourite artist/composer? ',
                answer: 'I’ve never really had a favourite. I always find new and inspiring artists but I also always go back to the old school legends. I would never be able to pick a favourite.                     ',
            },
            {
                question: 'What is your favourite music genre?',
                answer: 'I like and listen to a lot of different music. All genres have something special and different about them.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Could you share a memorable moment from your musical journey so far? ',
                answer: 'One very important moment for me was playing with my sister on an opera tour in Austria. It felt like I went full circle with my musical journey. I was finally able to sit next to the person who inspired me in a professional setting. It’s a very small moment but it felt extremely important for my musical development.                     ',
            },
            {
                question: 'How do you think music has evolved so far?',
                answer: 'Music is always evolving into new things. There is something out there for every single person to enjoy. There are so many artists, writers and performers and we all take inspiration and ideas from each other and create something new and interesting with them.                     ',
            },
            {
                question: 'What advice would you give to young musicians who want to pursue music as a career?',
                answer: 'Being a musician can be very difficult at times but it brings a sort of solitude and enjoyment to a person’s life. Always strive to be yourself and express yourself through your music.                    ',
            },
            {
                question: 'Can you share any upcoming projects you’re excited about? ',
                answer: 'One exciting project coming up is the Spring Gala organised by The Bulgarian Society in Groningen. We’ll be able to celebrate together an important Bulgarian holiday, have fun and enjoy some beautiful music together.',
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        id: 6,
        name: 'Anna-Maria Schitsova',
        title: 'Violin',
        age: 24,
        town: 'Sofia, Bulgaria',
        description: [
            {
                question: 'What initially inspired you to choose your music instrument and study it?',
                answer: 'I was in love with the sound of the violin since my parents would often take me to the concert hall with them. I was greatly inspired by Bulgarian violinist Svetlin Rusev, whose playing became my biggest motivation to make music my profession. ',
            },
            {
                question: 'Who is your favourite artist/composer? ',
                answer: 'Béla Bartók has to be among my favourites. He was not only a classics music composer but he was an ethnomusicologist and he implemented a lot of folklore elements in his music.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What is your favourite music genre?',
                answer: 'I am greatly inspired by folklore music, and not only from Bulgaria. European folklore, as a whole, is something I enjoy listening every day.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Could you share a memorable moment from your musical journey so far? ',
                answer: 'I have the opportunity to play in an ethno-funk formation, Tututu orchestra, that includes members from all around the world - from Bulgaria to Peru. With them I can experience the fusion of musical styles and the richness of our countries’ traditions. We had a great performance in Groningen’s Grand Theatre venue recently and upcoming tour in Germany this summer.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What advice would you give to young musicians who want to pursue music as a career?',
                answer: 'If you like what you do, don’t think too hard on the rest. Just concentrate on making music and hard work will pay off.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Can you share any upcoming projects you’re excited about? ',
                answer: 'I will have the opportunity to perform some arrangements of mine on an upcoming concert on the 24th of May about which I am very excited about. I’ve made arrangements of some of my favourite folklore songs and other famous Bulgarian music that I can’t wait to perform.',
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        id: 7,
        name: 'Stilyan Radev',
        title: 'Bass Guitar',
        age: 19,
        town: 'Ruse, Bulgaria',
        description: [
            {
                question: 'What initially inspired you to choose your music instrument and study it?',
                answer: 'I discovered the double bass when I was 9 year old and I was amazed by the grate sound and the variety of music you can play on it. So 10 years later I’m still learning it and I want to develop more in the jazz music. This is why I came to Groningen, so I can go further with my musical journey.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Who is your favourite artist/composer? ',
                answer: 'At the I would say in love with sound of Ray Brown and Christian McBride, but I get a lot inspiration from Miles Dāvis and Joe Henderson as well.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What is your favourite music genre?',
                answer: 'Contemporary jazz, bebop, fusion and R&B music.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Could you share a memorable moment from your musical journey so far? ',
                answer: 'The moment that I got accepted in conservatory to study jazz.',
            },
            {
                question: 'How do you think music has evolved so far?',
                answer: 'Music has many different paths and every path leads to different audiences so as a musician you choose which musical way to catch. Every genre have his own development.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What advice would you give to young musicians who want to pursue music as a career?',
                answer: 'I you really want to do something that you love, just be passionate about it and work work hard to achieve it. Happiness is the final result, promise!',
            },
            {
                question: 'Can you share any upcoming projects you’re excited about? ',
                answer: 'Festival in Germany; a lot of summer gig in Bulgaria and also Spring gala in May.',
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        id: 8,
        name: 'Stella Mihailova',
        title: 'Vocals',
        age: 20,
        town: 'Burgas, Bulgaria',
        description: [
            {
                question: 'What initially inspired you to choose your music instrument and study it?',
                answer: 'Since I was little I was very enthusiastic about learning music and began piano and vocal lessons. I specialised in vocals because It brings me joy and makes me feel fulfilled.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Who is your favourite artist/composer? ',
                answer: 'I’d say I have a lot of favourite artists, but one that is dearest to my heart would be Ella Fitzgerald, Betty Carter, Ray Bryant and Nina Simone.',
            },
            {
                question: 'What is your favourite music genre?',
                answer: 'Jazz.',
            },
            {
                question: 'How do you think music has evolved so far?',
                answer: 'I’d say it has evolved in many different ways and has a lot to offer.'
            },
            {
                question: 'What advice would you give to young musicians who want to pursue music as a career?',
                answer: 'Always keep yourself clean of fear and forced ideas, give it your best all the time and appreciate music for what it is.',
            },
            {
                question: 'Can you share any upcoming projects you’re excited about? ',
                answer: 'Concerts in the summer.',
            }
        ]
    },
];